University of Connecticut 1984.0018
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
University of Connecticut, Registrar's Office Records
1881-1997
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0018
476.65 Linear Feet
The Office of the Registrar compiles information about undergraduate courses and programs. The staff registers students, creates and maintains their records, provides certified documents, issues transcripts, processes grades, monitors NCAA student athletes' academic progress, and audits degrees. A significant portion of the collection is restricted from general use. In 2017, the Office of Graduate Records was incorporated into the Office of the Registrar.
Restrictions on Access
All records from this office are covered under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Information from these records is released only to authorized staff from the Registrar's Office. Limited access to some of the resetricted materials in the collection may be granted provided the request is for materials 75 or more years old or accompanied by proof of death of the individual whose records are being requested. Requests for access should be addressed to the University Archivist. Requests for official copies of transcripts, verification of grades, attendance and graduation should be addressed to the Registrar's Office.
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred to the University Archives from the Registrar's Office between 1984 and 2006.
Arrangement
Series I: Transcripts (1912-1977) contains original transcripts for students attending the University of Connecticut. These records are restricted for use by the Registrar's Office staff only until they are at least 75 years old (from the date of graduation or last enrollment) or the individual is deceased (proof of death required).
Series II: Grade Sheets (1920-1997) contain the official copy of grades submitted by faculty to be recorded on transcripts. These records are permanently restricted for use by the Registrar's Office staff only.
Series III: Co-Op High School Grade Sheets (1955-1997) contain the official copy of grades submitted by instructors teaching college level classes in high schools to be recorded in the University's records. These records are permanently restricted for use by the Registrar's Office staff only.
Series IV: Student Records (1884-1915) contain information equivalent to more modern transcripts.
Series V: Administrative Records (1931-1996) includes several forms sent to students between 1931 and 1935 as well as a lengthy run of enrollment reports.
History
The Office of the Registrar compiles information about undergraduate courses and programs. The staff registers students, creates and maintains their records, provides certified documents, issues transcripts, processes grades, monitors NCAA student athletes' academic progress, and audits degrees.
Services provided by the Office of the Registrar include course record management, classroom assignment, final exam scheduling, publication of the University's Undergraduate and Graduate Catalogs, academic record creation and maintenance, student registration, grade processing, transcript issuance, degree auditing for graduation, and monitoring of academic and administrative policies. Detailed information regarding the Registrar's Office location and services is available on their webpage.
Scope and Content
The collection contains records created and/or maintained by the Registrar's Office including transcripts, grade sheets, record books, and statistics.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and can be found in the Dodd Periodicals section of the collection:
University of Connecticut Bulletin (and all previous titles). Available online from the mid 20th century to the present.
Schedule of Classes. Dodd Periodicals
Administrative records; School Records; Connecticut (state); Education--Curricula; Universities and colleges; Storrs (inhabited place); University of Connecticut. Office of the Registrar; Storrs Agricultural College--Curricula.
- Series I: Transcripts, 1912-1977
  Conditions Governing Access
  Records that have reached the end of the restriction period may be requested by contacting the University Archivist.
  - Subseries A: Connecticut Agricultural College and Connecticut State College, 1912-1930s (Box 10-12, Box 67)
    These records have reached the end of their restriction period and may be requested by contacting the University Archivist.
  - Subseries B: University Extension, 1941-1944 (Box 67-68)
    Records that have reached the end of their restriction period may be requested by contacting the University Archivist.
  - Subseries C: Engineering, Science and Management War Training program, 1940s (Box 44-51, Box 52-59, Box 66)
  - Subseries D: Army Specialized Training Program, 1940s (Box 38-40, Box 61-62, Box 42-43, 60, 63)
  - Subseries E: New Haven PT Air Force, 1940s
  - Subseries F: University of Connecticut, 1925-1977 (Box 12-13, Box 1-10x, Box 30-37, Box 22-29, Box 14-21)
  - Subseries G: Microfilm, undated
    - Transcripts on microfilm (Box 2010.0065_1, Box 2010.0065_2, Box 1-2)
- Series II: Grade Sheets, 1920-1997 (Box 1-153, Box 1964-1969)
- Series III: Co-Op High School Grade Sheets, 1955-1997 (Box 1-9, Box 10-x)
- Series IV: Student Records, 1881-1915
  - Register of Students, 1884-1894 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Student Register and Record Book No. 1, 1894-1896 (Box 1)
  - Register of Students, 1895-1898 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Student Register and Record Book No. 2, 1896-1897 (Box 2)
  - Student Register and Record Book No. 3, 1897-1898 (Box 3)
  - Student Register and Record Book No. 4, 1898-1900 (Box 4)
  - Student Register and Record Book, 1898-1915
    - A - E (Box 5)
    - F - O (Box 6)
    - P - Z (Box 7)
  - Term Marks No. 1, 1881-1890 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Term Marks No. 2, 1890-1894 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Term Marks No. 3, 1894-1897 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Series V: Administrative Records, 1931-1996
  - [Note: Similar information is now available from the Office of Insitutional Research and Effectiveness website beginning in Fall 1991.]
  - Form letter to student, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Information for and about freshman, circa 1935 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Enrollment reports
    - Summer sessions, 1942, 1982, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Second semester, 1972 Spring (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Statistics, 1964, 1969, 1979, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Statistics, 1984 Spring (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Statistics, 1988 Fall (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Statistics, 1989 Spring - 1990 Spring (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Statistics, 1990 Fall (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Statistics, 1992 Fall (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Statistics, 1993 Spring (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Statistics, 1993 Fall (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Statistics, 1994 Spring (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Statistics, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Statistics, 1996 Spring (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Marjorie correspondence (Registrar), 1941-1943 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Registration forms, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Summer session survey, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Final Schedule of Classes, 1997-2000
    - Administrative Records, Correspondence, 1997-1998; 1.3 Linear Feet Portfolios organized by year. (Box 2002-0076_1)
      Scope and Content Note
      Subjects Include: Course List, Credits, Location and Time for Departments in years 1997 and 1998. Final Exam Schedule, Final Exam Policy.
    - Administrative Records, Correspondence, 1999-2000; 1.3 Linear Feet Portfolios organized by year. (Box 2002-0076_2)
      Subjects Include: Course List, Credits, Location and Time for Departments in years 1999 and 2000. Final Exam Schedule, Final Exam Policy.
    - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Notes, Spring 1998-Winter 1998; 0.5 Linear Feet Folders organized by semester. (Box 2002-0076_3)
      Subjects Include: Classroom: Requests, Scheduling and Reservations.
    - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Notes, Spring 1999-Winter1999; 0.5 Linear Feet Folders organized by semester. (Box 2002-0076_4)
    - Administrative Records, 2002; 0.25 Linear Feet (Box 2002-0076_5)
      Subjects Include: Final Schedule of Classes for Spring 2002